<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./c74ref.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<c74object name="airfx.density3~" module="MSP" category="distortion">

	<digest>
		Density3 refines Density to keep up with recent developments.
	</digest>

	<description>
		Density3 refines Density to keep up with recent developments.
	</description>

	<discussion>
		This secret weapon's seen a little fine-tuning.Density's one of my first plugins. Its power is in using sin() based overdrive combined with a very gentle highpass, one that can dial back the amount of saturation on heavy basses… while allowing it through anyhow using the dry/wet control. It's an incredible dirt-shaper for refined work.But what if it used the technique from PurestSaturation? That's Density3: finally an upgrade.But there's more! Turns out the negative Density range enjoys a change too: it blended better with a phase-flip. I could have known it needed one, except nobody constructs inverse saturations like this, as it doesn't seem like a useful sound. Until you take advantage of its gatey qualities to dial in tone, between -1 and 0, that keeps the nature of the tone the same but dries up its quieter regions, as subtly as you'd like.This is out because another dev I know was looking into Density2, and wanting to shoot it out against his own algorithms. I said, just so you know, there's a Density3 and it's on the github repository, it's just not out yet.Now it is :)
	</discussion>

	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name="author">Isabel Kaspriskie</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">Airwindows</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">distortion</metadata>
	</metadatalist>

	<inletlist>
		<inlet id="0" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Input L</digest>
		</inlet>
		<inlet id="1" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Input R</digest>
		</inlet>
	</inletlist>

	<outletlist>
		<outlet id="0" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Output L</digest>
		</outlet>
		<outlet id="1" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Output R</digest>
		</outlet>
		<outlet id="2" type="anything">
			<digest>Dump outlet</digest>
		</outlet>
	</outletlist>

	<methodlist>
		<method name="about">
			<digest>Get the original Airwindows "about" text for this object</digest>
			<description>
				Prints the original Airwindows description for this plugin out the
				dump outlet.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methodlist>

	<attributelist>
		<attribute name="density" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Density</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 0.
			</description>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name="highpas" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Highpas</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 0.
			</description>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name="output" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Output</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 1.
			</description>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name="dry/wet" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Dry/Wet</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 1.
			</description>
		</attribute>
	</attributelist>

</c74object>
