<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./c74ref.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<c74object name="airfx.znotch~" module="MSP" category="xyz-filters">

	<digest>
		ZNotch is a notch filter made to sound and act like the Emu e6400 Phaser.
	</digest>

	<description>
		ZNotch is a notch filter made to sound and act like the Emu e6400 Phaser.
	</description>

	<discussion>
		And finally, the fourth filter type (I’m doing basic filters, not trying to compete with real Z-Plane releases), ZNotch!This is made to sound like the Emu Phaser, which has notchlike qualities. At heart it’s an extension of the Airwindows Z series, not anything specifically Emu Z-Plane: I didn’t find a notch specifically in the Emu e6400 Ultra, but I thought the Phaser options were very notchlike, so I went for a take on those. You’ll get constant highs, the ability to notch out quite deep into the bass, and that overdrive that’s on tap in all the Airwindows Z plugins, plus the ability to do all that and then add that color, subtly, to the dry signal (do this by getting your distorted and notched tone just right, setting Poles to zero, turning the output up all the way and then bringing in just enough of the color that you can hear what it’s doing. Adjust to taste)This concludes the DnB-inspired sampler emulation EQs. Hopefully this bank of four Z-plugins will be handy to reach for, in the box, to get those vivid tones and grinds… I suspect I’ll find ’em useful in the place of more ‘normal’ EQs simply because the character of the distortion will be so handy. You don’t have to distort them, but since they take a little overdrive so nicely they’ll serve a purpose in all kinds of slight overdrive, or character adding, situations. And since they’re the Z series, you’ll know where to find them even if you’ve installed ALL the Airwindows plugins (and you can do that… if you dare!)
	</discussion>

	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name="author">Isabel Kaspriskie</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">Airwindows</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">xyz-filters</metadata>
	</metadatalist>

	<inletlist>
		<inlet id="0" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Input L</digest>
		</inlet>
		<inlet id="1" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Input R</digest>
		</inlet>
	</inletlist>

	<outletlist>
		<outlet id="0" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Output L</digest>
		</outlet>
		<outlet id="1" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Output R</digest>
		</outlet>
		<outlet id="2" type="anything">
			<digest>Dump outlet</digest>
		</outlet>
	</outletlist>

	<methodlist>
		<method name="about">
			<digest>Get the original Airwindows "about" text for this object</digest>
			<description>
				Prints the original Airwindows description for this plugin out the
				dump outlet.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methodlist>

	<attributelist>
		<attribute name="input" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Input</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 0.1.
			</description>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name="freq" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Freq</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 0.5.
			</description>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name="output" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Output</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 1.
			</description>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name="poles" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Poles</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 0.5.
			</description>
		</attribute>
	</attributelist>

</c74object>
