<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./c74ref.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<c74object name="airfx.facet~" module="MSP" category="effects">

	<digest>
		Facet is a new kind of hard clip that adds two sharp corners into the wave.
	</digest>

	<description>
		Facet is a new kind of hard clip that adds two sharp corners into the wave.
	</description>

	<discussion>
		Facet came out of me trying to come up with a new and distinct kind of distortion for the combined-distortions plugin I’m going to do. Rather than just bring Drive, Density, Spiral, Mojo etc. together, I wanted to add something different.So, Facet adds a ‘clip point’ but rather than a hard clip it just changes the ‘knee’ of the transfer function so your peaks can still go super high, way beyond 0 dB if you like.But, they change ‘angle’ at a sharp point which becomes sort of a corner in the sound. Except for high settings it’s both high up in the loudness, and a very gentle ‘corner’: still sharp, but very little change.And down near zero, it’s damn near total hard clipping. At silence, it literally is a hard clip to silence.Aw hell. Play with it, see what you think. i can’t explain this one well, at least not right now. The mad scientist labs have released another weird one. It will act like it’s a hard clip or a semi-dirty saturation, except the range of adjustment acts different, and it’ll throw an odd artifact on pure low-frequency tones… just play with it, see what you get. It will find its way into the combined plugin because it’s got a flavor all its own, but I can’t describe it today.
	</discussion>

	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name="author">Isabel Kaspriskie</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">Airwindows</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">effects</metadata>
	</metadatalist>

	<inletlist>
		<inlet id="0" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Input L</digest>
		</inlet>
		<inlet id="1" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Input R</digest>
		</inlet>
	</inletlist>

	<outletlist>
		<outlet id="0" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Output L</digest>
		</outlet>
		<outlet id="1" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Output R</digest>
		</outlet>
		<outlet id="2" type="anything">
			<digest>Dump outlet</digest>
		</outlet>
	</outletlist>

	<methodlist>
		<method name="about">
			<digest>Get the original Airwindows "about" text for this object</digest>
			<description>
				Prints the original Airwindows description for this plugin out the
				dump outlet.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methodlist>

	<attributelist>
		<attribute name="facet" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Facet</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 1.
			</description>
		</attribute>
	</attributelist>

</c74object>
