<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./c74ref.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<c74object name="airfx.tapefat~" module="MSP" category="filter">

	<digest>
		TapeFat is the tone control from TapeDelay.
	</digest>

	<description>
		TapeFat is the tone control from TapeDelay.
	</description>

	<discussion>
		TapeFat is just the tone control from TapeDelay. It works like an averaging filter that you can use to either roll off highs (or eventually mids), or subtract the effect to create a highpass and take out the lows.The reason this is interesting is, that tone control is completely bizarre. It’s an averaging filter, but on a pile of delay taps arranged according to prime numbers. Works more like an ambience control, but more densely packed. If you put an impulse through it you don’t get a smoothed-out lowpass so much as a bizarre micro-reverb. Since it’s using primes, it doesn’t reinforce any particular frequency. Since it’s an ambience, it doesn’t have any pre-echoes like linear phase EQs, and the artifacts it produces become a tone of their own (either in-phase, or inverted).You can hear it on the video, which has a number of things updated, not least this: the new audio is directly captured analog sorta-house music out of my livestreams. This way you ought to be able to really hear the way my plugins retain analog qualities, because now the demo music is essentially AAD: not products of other DAW mixes or digital synthesis, but source material.
	</discussion>

	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name="author">Isabel Kaspriskie</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">Airwindows</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">filter</metadata>
	</metadatalist>

	<inletlist>
		<inlet id="0" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Input L</digest>
		</inlet>
		<inlet id="1" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Input R</digest>
		</inlet>
	</inletlist>

	<outletlist>
		<outlet id="0" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Output L</digest>
		</outlet>
		<outlet id="1" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Output R</digest>
		</outlet>
		<outlet id="2" type="anything">
			<digest>Dump outlet</digest>
		</outlet>
	</outletlist>

	<methodlist>
		<method name="about">
			<digest>Get the original Airwindows "about" text for this object</digest>
			<description>
				Prints the original Airwindows description for this plugin out the
				dump outlet.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methodlist>

	<attributelist>
		<attribute name="lean/ft" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Lean/Ft</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 1.
			</description>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name="depth" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Depth</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 0.
			</description>
		</attribute>
	</attributelist>

</c74object>
