<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./c74ref.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<c74object name="airfx.tremolo~" module="MSP" category="effects">

	<digest>
		Tremolo is fluctuating saturation curves for a tubey tremolo.
	</digest>

	<description>
		Tremolo is fluctuating saturation curves for a tubey tremolo.
	</description>

	<discussion>
		So, you’ve probably got a tremolo built in to your DAW.But, if you’ve heard tremolo effects off classic records, it’s a whole different animal. DAW tremolos are neat little volume animations, capable of many cool effects (try making ’em squarewaves synced to the tempo for a nifty sequencey effect). But they don’t have that organic pulsating thing that takes a sound and gives it a whole new character.So I made this!This Tremolo uses saturation and antisaturation curves like you’d find in Density, and does the tremolo with that. It’s the same trick I use on the compressor ‘Pyewacket’. The result is, the loud parts develop a density and thickness mere volume won’t give you, and the lean parts hang on to a skeletal form of the transient attacks so your music comes through. This is not just ‘analog color’ like a coat of paint, Tremolo works quite differently from your DAW tremolo. It doesn’t sync to tempo, but that’s partly because I don’t know what to read (in AU and VST) that’d give me that information: could be added in future if the secrets are forthcoming, but there’s no sense withholding Tremolo just because of that!
	</discussion>

	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name="author">Isabel Kaspriskie</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">Airwindows</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">effects</metadata>
	</metadatalist>

	<inletlist>
		<inlet id="0" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Input L</digest>
		</inlet>
		<inlet id="1" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Input R</digest>
		</inlet>
	</inletlist>

	<outletlist>
		<outlet id="0" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Output L</digest>
		</outlet>
		<outlet id="1" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Output R</digest>
		</outlet>
		<outlet id="2" type="anything">
			<digest>Dump outlet</digest>
		</outlet>
	</outletlist>

	<methodlist>
		<method name="about">
			<digest>Get the original Airwindows "about" text for this object</digest>
			<description>
				Prints the original Airwindows description for this plugin out the
				dump outlet.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methodlist>

	<attributelist>
		<attribute name="speed" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Speed</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 0.5.
			</description>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name="depth" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Depth</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 1.
			</description>
		</attribute>
	</attributelist>

</c74object>
