<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./c74ref.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<c74object name="airfx.srsly~" module="MSP" category="stereo">

	<digest>
		Srsly is a psychoacoustic stereo processor.
	</digest>

	<description>
		Srsly is a psychoacoustic stereo processor.
	</description>

	<discussion>
		People get really excited sometimes, so here’s a failure :)Srsly is meant to do what a Hughes SRS processor does. That’s an obscure stereo widener actually made by Howard “Spruce Goose” Hughes’ company. I tackled it because a musician I love, Chad Clark, needs one ‘cos his is broken and not in proper working order. Hence, the need for somebody to try and do a plugin version. So I tried, with some pictures out of Popular Mechanics and a single cruddy youtube video to be my guide (this thing is OBSCURE) and I have not succeeded. Whatever the real one sounds like, this ain’t it.But it does a thing, and I’ve added a Q control to help get it to do useful things since I can’t tell what’s right or wrong for this stuff, and this is as far as I can carry it right now. The source is MIT licensed for anyone else who’d like to pick up where I left off, and quite a bit of basic information is shown in the curves of that Popular Mechanics article about the thing, and it is kinda neat: accentuate comb-filtery effects you get from the shapes of your own ears. It does do a thing, that’s not like any other stereo effect I know of. And I ought to be able to use some of the tech from this to do subtle stereo-field enhancements in future versions of Console, stuff like that. You can refine it down to basic concepts and apply those.(followup: this remains useful for more subtle stereo spatiality things)
	</discussion>

	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name="author">Isabel Kaspriskie</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">Airwindows</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">stereo</metadata>
	</metadatalist>

	<inletlist>
		<inlet id="0" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Input L</digest>
		</inlet>
		<inlet id="1" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Input R</digest>
		</inlet>
	</inletlist>

	<outletlist>
		<outlet id="0" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Output L</digest>
		</outlet>
		<outlet id="1" type="signal">
			<digest>(signal) Output R</digest>
		</outlet>
		<outlet id="2" type="anything">
			<digest>Dump outlet</digest>
		</outlet>
	</outletlist>

	<methodlist>
		<method name="about">
			<digest>Get the original Airwindows "about" text for this object</digest>
			<description>
				Prints the original Airwindows description for this plugin out the
				dump outlet.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methodlist>

	<attributelist>
		<attribute name="center" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Center</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 0.
			</description>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name="space" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Space</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 0.
			</description>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name="level" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Level</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 1.
			</description>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name="q" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Q</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 0.5.
			</description>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name="dry/wet" get="1" set="1" type="float64" size="1">
			<digest>Dry/Wet</digest>
			<description>
				Range 0.0-1.0. Default 1.
			</description>
		</attribute>
	</attributelist>

</c74object>
